<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>@Spirotot | Aaron Fields</title><description>@Spirotot | Aaron Fields</description><link>http://blog.spirotot.com/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:16:42 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.spirotot.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>For Reference: My Old YouTube Videos</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven't made any YouTube videos since I was in school, but if you're interested in learning some really basic exploitation skillz (primarily stack-based exploitation), here's a link to check out my videos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Spirotot1/videos"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/Spirotot1/videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.spirotot.com/2014/12/08/for-reference-my-old-youtube-videos/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">f30f1c08-9bf7-4c88-8c90-b305264742ca</guid><dc:creator>Aaron Fields</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:16:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Beating the Cloud with Your Command Prompt</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I've been spending more and more time working in, on, and around UNIX-based operating systems over the past two years or so, and, though I'm &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; quite a noob, I've have been working on making myself faster and better at using shells on Linux. I've recently adopted &lt;a href="http://www.zsh.org/"&gt;Zsh&lt;/a&gt; as my go-to shell for my personal/development machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you've not yet tried Zsh, I'd highly recommend checking it out. &lt;a href="http://fendrich.se/blog/2012/09/28/no/"&gt;People rave about it&lt;/a&gt;, and there's a wonderful tool called &lt;a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh"&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;/a&gt; that makes installing/maintaining it a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it's obvious that software developers use the shell for developer-y things. But what about 'normal people things'? I want to share an example of how even a rudimentary familiarity with some basic Linux command-line utilities can make some tasks much easier and faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our wedding videographer (my brother-in-law) uploaded all 40GB of our wedding ceremony videos up on... &lt;a href="https://onedrive.live.com/"&gt;Microsoft OneDrive&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blog.spirotot.com/content/images/2014/11/Selection_002.png" alt="OneDrive File Listing"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are nearly 300 video files in there... Fortunately, OneDrive does let you check multiple files to be compressed into a zip for download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, one might tick the checkboxes for all the files on the page, expecting that all of the files will be downloaded at once. They will be very disappointed to find, after having waiting for minutes to hours (depending on the speed of your Internet connection) that OneDrive will cut off the size of the zip file at 4GB. One might be rather annoyed. That one might be me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I downloaded the files in chunks of 25 or so movies at a time. Painful, but not as painful as 1 at a time... especially since OneDrive will only let you have 4 HTTP download streams running simultaneously. The fun never ends with with the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, once all the zips are finally done downloading, and I've extracted all the videos... I notice that at least one of the zip files had been larger than 4GB, which means that I didn't get all the videos for that batch. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ungh...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point I had two basic options. I could manually check/verify the ~265 files I had gotten with the ones shown in OneDrive in my browser to see which ones I was missing. The sequence numbers in the filenames are non-contiguous (even in OneDrive), making this option extra not-fun and error-prone. I don't know how long this would take, but it seemed like it'd take way too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, I could try to use the tools I have at-hand to automatically solve this problem in a matter of minutes. Of course, that is what I did. Here's how. This should work in Bash or Zsh, by the way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need to know what files I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have. I want them saved in a file called &lt;code&gt;mvi_list&lt;/code&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;OneDrive knows that. I used &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/"&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt; to save the OneDrive page's contents (Options -&gt; Save Page As). It's useful to note that the mobile OneDrive page is less AJAX-y, and will probably give you a more reliable result. Use a &lt;a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/user-agent-switcher-for-c/djflhoibgkdhkhhcedjiklpkjnoahfmg?hl=en-US"&gt;User-Agent switcher&lt;/a&gt; to load the mobile site in your desktop browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We know that all the video names start with "MVI_". We can extract the video names from the HTML file using that string, plus some dirty hacks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat [htmlfile] | tr " " "\n" | grep "MVI_" | grep "alt" | sort | uniq | tr -d "alt=\"" &amp;gt; mvi_list.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't know what the vertical bars (pipes) are, read about them here &lt;a href="http://tldp.org/HOWTO/Bash-Prog-Intro-HOWTO-4.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat [htmlfile] |&lt;/code&gt; reads the contents of your HTML file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tr " " "\n" |&lt;/code&gt; replaces whitespace with a newline character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;grep "MVI_" |&lt;/code&gt; filters out any lines that have the filenames that we're interested in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;grep "alt" |&lt;/code&gt; filters out any lines that have the HTML &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; attribute, as it so happens that these lines contain our filenames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sort |&lt;/code&gt; sorts the lines alphabetically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;uniq |&lt;/code&gt; deduplicates the lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;tr -d "alt=\"" &amp;gt; mvi_list&lt;/code&gt; removes the characters contained in the quotes from each line, and save the final result in a file called &lt;code&gt;mvi_list&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need the list of the video files that I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have. I want it saved in a file called &lt;code&gt;haves&lt;/code&gt;. I have all the video files saved in a folder called &lt;code&gt;extracted&lt;/code&gt;. They're named &lt;code&gt;MVI_[sequenceNumber].MOV&lt;/code&gt;. The filenames in &lt;code&gt;mvi_list&lt;/code&gt; do not have the .MOV extension. So, I'll use the following command to get a list of the files I have in the same format as &lt;code&gt;mvi_list&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls extracted | awk -F"." '{print $1}' &amp;gt; haves
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls extracted |&lt;/code&gt; gives me a simple list of all the files I have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;awk -F"." '{print $1}' &amp;gt; haves&lt;/code&gt; splits up each line at the period, and prints the first (&lt;code&gt;$1&lt;/code&gt;) chunk of the split, which is the filename in this case. This gets saved into a file called &lt;code&gt;haves&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now I can check to see what the difference between OneDrive and my local filesystem is, using &lt;code&gt;diff mvi_list haves&lt;/code&gt;, which will compare the two files passed to it, displaying any differences. This produces the following output:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;37,40d36
&amp;lt; MVI_6898
&amp;lt; MVI_6899
&amp;lt; MVI_6900
&amp;lt; MVI_6901
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means that &lt;code&gt;mvi_list&lt;/code&gt; has 4 items that &lt;code&gt;haves&lt;/code&gt; does not. Those are the videos I'm missing! I'm sure there are more elegant solutions, but as it is, this took all of 2 minutes; the missing movies are downloaded, and my problem is solved without any tedious manual comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google will usually provide answers for any questions you have about using Bash/Zsh to solve otherwise tedious problems (i.e. "How do I rename all the files in a folder?"). I'd also recommend checking out &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/climagic"&gt;Command Line Magic&lt;/a&gt; for further inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.spirotot.com/2014/11/26/beating-the-cloud-with-your-command-prompt/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9ef8e1-a4c4-4e23-ac86-797bfa776617</guid><category>bash</category><category>zsh</category><category>linux</category><dc:creator>Aaron Fields</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 21:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cycling Is Awesome</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blog.spirotot.com/content/images/2014/11/IMG_20141120_191542239-1.jpg" alt="2015 Motobecane Fantom Cross Outlaw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I put my 200th mile on my new bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-way through last month,  I decided I wanted to start biking to work. And so I spent a few days researching like crazy trying to decide what type of bike to ride. I landed on the &lt;a href="http://www.bikesdirect.com/products/motobecane/outlaw-discbrake-crossbikes.htm"&gt;2015 Motobecane Fantom Cross Outlaw&lt;/a&gt;. Light aluminum frame (no worries about rust), decent Shimano shifters/derailleurs, all-weather disk brakes, and braze-ons for fenders and racks. A great all around bike, and especially great for my short but hilly commute. And all for a good price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now November, and getting a little chilly... so one might ask, why now, of all times, would one want to start commuting to work via bicycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reasoning revolved around the following thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm fully convinced that cycling (especially if we sell one of our two vehicles) will be a wise &lt;a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2013/06/13/bicycling-the-safest-form-of-transportation/"&gt;financial &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; physical investment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I make it through the winter, I think it's safe to say that I'll stick with cycling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to be outside more/fend off cabin fever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's good exercise, which is something I've been struggling with since finishing college.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've biked every day so far this month except for four. Two of those were rest days. I didn't have time to bike another. And the last day... I wussed out because it was really cold and raining hard. But, it's been awesome. It's been in the mid-20's outside the past few days... and I love it. Every day feels like an accomplishment, and &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; every day I am a little faster. I get to breathe more fresh air, see more trees, and feel more wind. It's wonderfully satisfying, and I look forward to my ride each morning more than I ever thought I would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, I'm less than a month in... so maybe the thrill is in the newness of it all and will wear off with time... but I doubt it. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the following equipment to make commuting easier -- after all, if it's miserable experience, I'm not sure I'd be able to will myself do it long-term. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00D9B7OKQ/"&gt;A bike stand&lt;/a&gt; - awesome for assembling and tuning my bike. Would have been a real pain without.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0012Q41HY/"&gt;Multi-tool&lt;/a&gt; - highly recommended around the Internet... figured this would be good to have for any quick adjustments on the road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001AT33CW/"&gt;Combo pedals&lt;/a&gt; - I don't have or wear cleats yet, and probably won't 'til the summer at the soonest... so these seemed like a future-proof option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000AO7ETQ"&gt;Helmet mirror&lt;/a&gt; - Yep, it makes me look like a goof... but it is nice to not have to twist all the way around on my bike to see behind me. I got the compact version, but wish I would have gotten the regular one. The compact version feels a little too small/short.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0041XA1D8"&gt;Fenders&lt;/a&gt; - Great for those puddly and/or slushy days. These are awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FIAVHE"&gt;Rack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000ZKES0S/"&gt;bag/panniers&lt;/a&gt; - rack seems solid, and the bag's panniers are large enough for my laptop/s. I've heard this bag doesn't hold up the best, and it's not water&lt;em&gt;proof&lt;/em&gt; without the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Topeak-Trunk-Bicycle-Rain-Cover/dp/B000ZKAU0A/"&gt;rain cover&lt;/a&gt;... just water resistant. But, so far, I've been very happy with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00E1NQ696/"&gt;Lights&lt;/a&gt; - so I can see and be seen. These lights are really bright, and seem pretty slick so far. &lt;a href="http://thesweethome.com/reviews/best-commuter-bike-lights/"&gt;The SweetHome likes them, too.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things mentioned in the post may or may not warrant a more detailed post in the future, especially as things wear and age -- I'm interested in the longevity and durability of things like the bag, and the lights. They get used every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you could have the same setup for less than $1,500 up front. I bet that's cheaper than any car you're looking at. Quite possibly more fun, too. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.spirotot.com/2014/11/20/cycling/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">22152395-1063-491e-8e0f-db3da50beac4</guid><category>cycling</category><category>bicycles</category><dc:creator>Aaron Fields</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:11:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blog Is Up!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks mostly to &lt;a href="http://www.sitepoint.com/create-static-ghost-blog-buster/"&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://me.net.nz/blog/github-pages-secure-with-cloudflare/"&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; for getting me set up seemingly properly. &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;Free hosting&lt;/a&gt;, free SSL (via GitHub or &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/ssl"&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;), a &lt;a href="https://ghost.org/"&gt;simple and open-source blog&lt;/a&gt; for writing/publishing, though all you see are fast and secure &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/buster/0.1"&gt;static pages&lt;/a&gt; that are capabable of supporting &lt;a href="https://disqus.com/"&gt;dynamic comments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much &lt;em&gt;cloud&lt;/em&gt; that I can feel it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.spirotot.com/2014/11/19/blog-is-up/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">2b89c936-3732-4bef-bb00-4359f782cca3</guid><category>SSL</category><category>github</category><category>cloudflare</category><category>disqus</category><category>ghost</category><category>cloud</category><dc:creator>Aaron Fields</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 04:41:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>