<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>@Spirotot | Aaron Fields</title><description>@Spirotot | Aaron Fields</description><link>http://blog.spirotot.com/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:23:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.spirotot.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Cycling Is Awesome</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blog.spirotot.com/content/images/2014/11/IMG_20141120_191542239-1.jpg" alt="2015 Motobecane Fantom Cross Outlaw"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I put my 200th mile on my new bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-way through last month,  I decided I wanted to start biking to work. And so I spent a few days researching like crazy trying to decide what type of bike to ride. I landed on the &lt;a href="http://www.bikesdirect.com/products/motobecane/outlaw-discbrake-crossbikes.htm"&gt;2015 Motobecane Fantom Cross Outlaw&lt;/a&gt;. Light aluminum frame (no worries about rust), decent Shimano shifters/derailleurs, all-weather disk brakes, and braze-ons for fenders and racks. A great all around bike, and especially great for my short but hilly commute. And all for a good price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now November, and getting a little chilly... so one might ask, why now, of all times, would one want to start commuting to work via bicycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reasoning revolved around the following thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I'm fully convinced that cycling (especially if we sell one of our two vehicles) will be a wise &lt;a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2013/06/13/bicycling-the-safest-form-of-transportation/"&gt;financial &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; physical investment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I make it through the winter, I think it's safe to say that I'll stick with cycling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to be outside more/fend off cabin fever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's good exercise, which is something I've been struggling with since finishing college.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've biked every day so far this month except for four. Two of those were rest days. I didn't have time to bike another. And the last day... I wussed out because it was really cold and raining hard. But, it's been awesome. It's been in the mid-20's outside the past few days... and I love it. Every day feels like an accomplishment, and &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; every day I am a little faster. I get to breathe more fresh air, see more trees, and feel more wind. It's wonderfully satisfying, and I look forward to my ride each morning more than I ever thought I would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, I'm less than a month in... so maybe the thrill is in the newness of it all and will wear off with time... but I doubt it. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the following equipment to make commuting easier -- after all, if it's miserable experience, I'm not sure I'd be able to will myself do it long-term. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00D9B7OKQ/"&gt;A bike stand&lt;/a&gt; - awesome for assembling and tuning my bike. Would have been a real pain without.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0012Q41HY/"&gt;Multi-tool&lt;/a&gt; - highly recommended around the Internet... figured this would be good to have for any quick adjustments on the road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001AT33CW/"&gt;Combo pedals&lt;/a&gt; - I don't have or wear cleats yet, and probably won't 'til the summer at the soonest... so these seemed like a future-proof option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000AO7ETQ"&gt;Helmet mirror&lt;/a&gt; - Yep, it makes me look like a goof... but it is nice to not have to twist all the way around on my bike to see behind me. I got the compact version, but wish I would have gotten the regular one. The compact version feels a little too small/short.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0041XA1D8"&gt;Fenders&lt;/a&gt; - Great for those puddly and/or slushy days. These are awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FIAVHE"&gt;Rack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000ZKES0S/"&gt;bag/panniers&lt;/a&gt; - rack seems solid, and the bag's panniers are large enough for my laptop/s. I've heard this bag doesn't hold up the best, and it's not water&lt;em&gt;proof&lt;/em&gt; without the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Topeak-Trunk-Bicycle-Rain-Cover/dp/B000ZKAU0A/"&gt;rain cover&lt;/a&gt;... just water resistant. But, so far, I've been very happy with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00E1NQ696/"&gt;Lights&lt;/a&gt; - so I can see and be seen. These lights are really bright, and seem pretty slick so far. &lt;a href="http://thesweethome.com/reviews/best-commuter-bike-lights/"&gt;The SweetHome likes them, too.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things mentioned in the post may or may not warrant a more detailed post in the future, especially as things wear and age -- I'm interested in the longevity and durability of things like the bag, and the lights. They get used every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you could have the same setup for less than $1,500 up front. I bet that's cheaper than any car you're looking at. Quite possibly more fun, too. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.spirotot.com/2014/11/20/cycling/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">22152395-1063-491e-8e0f-db3da50beac4</guid><category>cycling</category><category>bicycles</category><dc:creator>Aaron Fields</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:11:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Blog is up!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks mostly to &lt;a href="http://www.sitepoint.com/create-static-ghost-blog-buster/"&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://me.net.nz/blog/github-pages-secure-with-cloudflare/"&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; for getting me set up seemingly properly. &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;Free hosting&lt;/a&gt;, free SSL (via GitHub or &lt;a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/ssl"&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;), a &lt;a href="https://ghost.org/"&gt;simple and open-source blog&lt;/a&gt; for writing/publishing, though all you see are fast and secure &lt;a href="https://pypi.python.org/pypi/buster/0.1"&gt;static pages&lt;/a&gt; that are capabable of supporting &lt;a href="https://disqus.com/"&gt;dynamic comments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much &lt;em&gt;cloud&lt;/em&gt; that I can feel it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://blog.spirotot.com/2014/11/19/blog-is-up/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">2b89c936-3732-4bef-bb00-4359f782cca3</guid><category>SSL</category><category>github</category><category>cloudflare</category><category>disqus</category><category>ghost</category><category>cloud</category><dc:creator>Aaron Fields</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 04:41:07 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>